Hi, I'm Ken Kashabura, personal trainer and free lance fitness writer, and this is how to duck walk.
What you do whenever you are trying to do your duck walk, is you want to start with your feet shoulder width apart.
With your feet shoulder width apart, you're going to squat down nice and deep.
When you take your first step, you're going to step forward, and you want to get that front foot flat on the floor, and your back foot is going to be on the toe.
And then you're going to continue from there, one foot after the other, with the front foot being flat on the floor.
Now what you want to do as well, with your arms, is you want to take your arms and you want to get 'em from your ear to the side of your hip, and keep 'em in tight.
And you're going, each step, the opposite arm is coming with you, just like...just like you're running.
So if you're running, it's the same hand motion, okay?
Duck walks are good for sprinting, to help with the flexibility in there, and they're also good for wrestling if you're trying to do the shoot, take your opponent down, then you'll be able to have the flexibility and still maintain strength during the flexibility while you're reaching for your shoot.
A lot of times people say that duck walking is bad for your knees, and if you have pre-existing knee injuries, then yes, you probably shouldn't do duck walks.
But if you do not have any pre-existing knee injuries, duck walks are fine.
I'm Ken Kashabura and that's how to duck walk.